<!--

This is a the help file for the main index page.

$Id: index.xml,v 1.1.1.1 2010-01-25 15:47:29 tharris Exp $

Sheldon McKay <mckays@cshl.edu>

-->

<xml>
  <section section_id="Genome">
  <![CDATA[
  <b>Genome:</b> Browse the <i>C. elegans</i> and other genomes
  with the Generic Genome Browser, a part of the Generic Model
  Organism Database (GMOD) project.
  ]]>
 </section>

  <section section_id="Blast / Blat">
  <![CDATA[
  <b>BLAST/BLAT:</b> Search for a sequence in protein, genomic DNA
  and EST databases. <font color=green>NOTE: A new user interface 
  has been released.</font>
  ]]>
 </section>

  <section section_id="WormMart">
  <![CDATA[
   <b>WormMart:</b> A data mining resource that provides easy and interactive 
   access to data en masse. In particular, WormMart enables users to retrieve 
   sequences and genome annotations using a variety of filters to constrain 
   retrieved results. <font color=green>NOTE: An improved user interface has
   been released.</font>
  ]]>
 </section>

  <section section_id="Markers">
  <![CDATA[
   <b>Markers:</b> This page is designed to assist in the selection of SNPS and visible
   genetic markers for mapping experiments. Provided with a genetic interval, it will
   display all visible markers and SNPs within that interval, as well as strains
   carrying those SNPs
  ]]>
  </section>

  <section section_id="Batch Sequences">
  <![CDATA[
   <b>Batch Sequences:</b> A batch sequence dumper that allows you to export sequences
   with various types of filters.
  ]]>
  </section>

  <section section_id="Genetic Maps">
  <![CDATA[
    <b>Genetic Maps:</b> Examine chromosomes and genetic intervals with this ACeDB-style
    genetic map viewer.
  ]]>
  </section>

  <section section_id="Submit">
  <![CDATA[
   <b>Submit data to Wormbase:</b>  We offer multiple submission options
   and can also provide assistance in formatting and processing for easy incorporation
   into WormBase. By submitting your data to WormBase, you help to ensure its long-term
   availability as well as place it within a rich, highly cross-referenced context.
   <p>Click this link for more information.
  ]]>
  </section>

  <section section_id="Searches">
  <![CDATA[
    <b>Searches</b> A portal to the various types of simple and complex searches
    that can be done in WormBase.  <p>Look here if you are interested in bulk data, data
    mining and more sophisticated WormBase queries.
  ]]>
  </section>

 <section section_id="Literature"> 
  <![CDATA[
    <b>Literature Search:</b> Perform a detailed
    search of <i>C. elegans</i> papers and abstracts
    with Textpresso.
  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="XML">
  <![CDATA[
   <b>Results as XML:</b> For power users/data miners.  This
   option will dump the data directly from the acedb database object
   in XML format.<br>You may also wish to consider using WormMart.
  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Suggest">
  <![CDATA[
  <b>Wormbase Suggest:</b> Based on what you type, 
  wormbase does a quick database search and suggests
  optimized queries.<br>
  <ul style="padding-top:10px;font-size:90%;margin-left:0">
  <li>You can ignore the suggestions.
  <br>
  <li>To choose a selection, use your mouse or arrow down and hit 'enter'.
  <br>
  <li>Uncheck this box to disable autocompletion.
  </ul>
  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Exact">
  <![CDATA[
  <b>Exact match:</b> Selecting this option will force the
  database search to consider only results that exactly match the
  query phrase.  For example, an exact search would look for
  'pharyngeal gland cell' <i>vs.</i> 'pharyngeal', 'gland' and/or 'cell'.
  ]]>
 </section>

</xml>
